Guide to the Gladys A. Sperling papers, 1929-1987.
Sperling, Gladys A. papers, 1929-1987
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gladys A. Sperling papers, 1929-1987.
21-14-3324
Gladys Athena Sperling, 1903-
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, subject files, clippings, notebooks, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence files, subject files, talks and papers, reprints (both those in which Sperling is a co-author and ones by Clive McCay), and clippings. Also student notebooks, particularly in bacteriology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Research assistant in nutrition.
After receiving an M.S. degree in bacteriology from Cornell in 1936, Miss Sperling was hired by Professor Clive McCay to assist him in nutritional studies. She was responsible for rats and other laboratory animals, supervised graduate students and other technicians, mixed animal feed, answered correspondence, created exhibits, helped take blood samples, and arranged for photography. She is credited as a co-author on many scientific papers on foods, nutrition, health, and longevity. Gladys Sperling died on January 17, 2003.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence files, subject files, talks and papers, reprints (both those in which Sperling is a co-author and ones by Clive McCay), and clippings. Also student notebooks, particularly in bacteriology.
Included is a subject file on Professor Loren Petry and photographs relating to the Nobel Prize award to James Sumner.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sperling, Gladys Athena,1903-; McCay, Clive Maine, 1898-1967.; Petry, Loren Clifford, 1887-; Sumner, James B.(James Batcheller), 1887-1955.
Subjects:
Aging--Nutritional aspects.; Animal nutrition.; Animals--Research.; Nutrition--Research.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Subject Files
Series III. Articles, Papers, Talks
Series IV. Photographs
Series V. Reprints
Series VI. Coursework
Series VII. Experiments
Series VIII. Miscellany
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence re Christmas newsletter, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Vitamin A, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Vitamin D, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Christmas newsletter and Easter, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence pertaining to hamsters, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence pertaining to hamsters (o/s), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Madison County Health Council, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Dr. Fred Miller, 1949-1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - Dr. Smith - teeth, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series II. Subject Files
  - Notes on A.M.A. meeting, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Animal nutrition, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Arthritis, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Atlantic City, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - [New] Building, 1947-1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1938-1973 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Coffee experiment, 19 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Conferences, 19 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Equipment, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Holiday newsletters - Animal Nutrition, 19 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Humor, 19 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Lab schedules, etc., 19 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Schedule notes, 19 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Lifetime living, 19 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Nutritional requirements conference, 19 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Personal, 19 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Petry, Loren, 19 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Dr. Pope, Brown, Blaustein, 19 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Series III. Articles, Papers, Talks
  - Publications, 19 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dr. Pope's paper, 19 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Popular Science, 19 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Sex steroids on rats, 19 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Papers, 19 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Talks, 19 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Photos, 1951-1967 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Photos - conferences, 1927-1954 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Photos - rats, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Photos - Sumner Nobel Prize, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Series V. Reprints
  - Sperling reprints, 1939-1949 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Sperling reprints, 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Sperling reprints, 1960-1978 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - McCay reprints, 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - McCay reprints, 1931-1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - McCay reprints, 1940-1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McCay reprints, 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - McCay reprints, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - McCay reprints, 1960-1963; 1973; 19-- (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - McCay biographical material and miscellany, 1946-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series VI. Coursework
  - Student notes, 1933; 19-- (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bacteriology, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Biochemistry, histology, 1931; 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Geology - summer session, 19-- (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bacteriology 105, 193- (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bacteriology 211, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Bacteriology 213, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bacteriology, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bacteriology lab manual, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dairy bacteriology, 19-- (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Lab notes, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series VII. Experiments
  - Animal nutrition, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Manganese experiment, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Longevity - retarded growth, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Animal nutrition - dairy, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Dry matter balance, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Egg experiments, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Retardation - exercise, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Rats on mink diets, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series VIII. Miscellany
  - Small Animal Lab guest book, 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Account books, 1936; 1946 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Collier's article re Clive McCay, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Certificates, 1944; 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)